Christine (Chris) Bohnet

christine.bohnet@gmail.com Council Bluffs, IA 712-326-5215

Visit https://cmbohnet.github.io/PersonalProfile/ for an interactive resume experience.

SUMMARY

Lead Analyst, Software Developer & QA Test Engineer with extensive experience in system requirements, development, test and implementation that delivers both quality software solutions within budget and is customer-focused from definition to delivery. Experienced in functional testing, regression testing, end to end testing, optimization and performance testing, user acceptance testing and integration testing.

Strong interpersonal skills to meet with customers and interfacing systems. Extensive experience in Agile methodology.

Experienced in all aspects and roles of SDLC: analysis, design, development, testing, project management, delivery and production support.

Future goals are to seek a remote or partially remote position where I may continue dependable and superior test or development deliveries, as well as learning and discovering new opportunities or technologies with customer and quality delivery as the primary focus.

SOFTWARE / TECHNICAL SKILLS

Platforms: Web, Unix, Linux, Windows, Mainframe

Languages: J2EE/JAVA, JDBC, JMS, Log4j, XML, HTML5, CSS3, C#, JSON, XSLT with training in AngularJS &

TypeScript

Scripting: Groovy, UNIX Shell Scripting, Javascript

Web/Application Server: Tomcat, Apache

Messaging Services: Tibco Bus / Business Works, MQ Series, SOAP/REST

Database: Oracle, DB2, Microsoft DB, SQL

Development Tools: Eclipse, SSH Client, CVS, Dimensions, Caliber, MDW Framework, Resolve Framework

<u>Documentation Tools</u>: CAAC, Microsoft visio, PowerPoint, Microsoft Office Test Tools: Quality Center, LoadRunner, JUnit with training in Selenium

Mainframe Languages/Tools: COBOL, MQ Series, JCL, TSO/ISPF, Librarian, Endevor, File-AID, Xpediter, Spufi,

QMF

EXPERIENCE

4/2015 – 4/2018 Consulting IBM, US

Consultant: Developer, Analyst, QA Tester, Delivery

- Support CenturyLink Einstein Knova application and EOSL project requiring Java support on a Windows
 client-based vendor application. Required strong communication and troubleshooting skills in interfacing
 with vendors and clients to resolve authoring issues.
- Developer/QA Tester on OCEANS Resolve Team 2 Network Project in Resolve application requiring SOAP, Java, Groovy, Tibco, database, CRON, DB Triggers, UCF commands. Project managed in CAAC governed by Agile. Created user stories, tasks, estimates, QMS diagrams.
- Increased efficiency of network technicians by defining and delivering both an automated solution and user interface to programmatically run UCF command sequences on network routers and update trouble tickets.
- Collaborated with business clients, interfacing systems, vendors and development to define business processes and functional requirements to design effective IT solutions.
- Created and maintained a flexible/scalable test-driven development framework utilizing shell scripts, CRON jobs, DB triggers and dynamic properties for Functional/Unit testing and reviewed all results ensuring accuracy, clarity and completeness.

- Built DB tables populated with dynamic table-driven test data in Oracle and Microsoft.
- Performed Regression Testing with both internally built code and interfacing systems for enhancements, bug fixes and software or environmental upgrades.
- Coordinated End to End (E2E) testing with complex interfacing systems in addition to ensuring data or access is available in test and production environments at all times.
- Led User Acceptance Testing (UAT) for both internal and external clients including collaborating with security and complying to company standards.
- Performed Optimization Testing in various environments including determining Tibco / Business Works
 configurations, MQ Series queue configurations, and testing users and query throughput for both web
 service and database optimization and connection timeout for SLA's.
- Identified, tracked and documented test cases, expected results, actual results, defects, root cause, solutions and expected delivery and communicated back to the project team, stakeholder and release team for rapid delivery by sprint end.
- Prepared and maintained user reference and training documentation.
- Created QMS and needed documentation as well as experience with Agile in creating user stories, tasks and estimates.
- Member of the Agile Development team composed of onshore and offshore members and participated in the Agile ceremonies: sprint planning, daily scrum meetings, iteration review, and retrospective.

6/1999 - 4/2015 Telecommunications CenturyLink, US

Analyst, Developer, QA Tester, Delivery

- Collaborated with clients, QA testers, production support, change management and vendors in all
 phases of the SDLC while assuming all roles including project manager, analyst, developer, QA tester
 and release management.
- Analyzed business systems and collaborated with users and subject matter experts to align the software solutions with business programs
- Interacted with stakeholders to define and document Business Requirements,
- Designed, built, and maintained efficient, reusable, and reliable code based on design specifications and created supporting low-level, high-level design documents and flow diagrams while keeping disaster recovery documentation current.
- Maintained health of test environments to detect, diagnose, manage and monitor by various methods
 including adding alarms of system and interfacing systems to be responsive, test data to be current and
 user password to be authenticated for end user, application server and DB.
- Built and communicated test plans with various development groups for complex systems that involved database administrators, front end, back end applications and applications built with MQ Series, Tibco, SOAP and REST services.
- Organized integration testing with multiple interfacing environments such as mainframe, Unix, Windows and web services.
- Built test cases / plans according to user stories, analyzed business requirements and design documents for completeness and testability and led reviews of test documents with clients, developers and release team.
- White box and black box testing for success and successful fail testing.
- Acquired Visio skills to create process flows and mapping.
- Developed CMMI document, code and file naming standards and storage organization solutions that contributed to achieving the next CMMI level for the company and recommended changes to established processes and policies.
- 2015–2004 Developed, tested and supported Java, JavaScript, .Net, Visual Basic, Tibco, MQ Series, web technologies, SQL, XML, HTML, Quality Center and various tools and technologies.
- 2004 1999 Developed, tested and supported COBOL, JCL, DB2, MQ, TSO, ISPF, QMF, Spufi, Endevor, Xpediter, File-AID mainframe technologies..

EDUCATION

Bachelors, Management Information Systems with Minors in Computer Science and Psychology Iowa State University, US, 1992. Graduated with Honors and Distinction.

| Currently pursuing Web development bachelor de 2020. | egree at Bellevue | University to be completed | I in November |
|--|-------------------|----------------------------|---------------|
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |
| | | | |